randolphusa.com 2018-09-04

# Privacy Policy | Randolph Engineering

_Last modified: 08/15/2018_

 **Introduction**

Randolph Engineering Eyewear ( **“Randolph”** or **  “We”** or **“Us”** ) takes its responsibility to protect and respect your privacy seriously, and wants to make sure that you understand how we use your data.

This policy describes the types of information Randolph may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the website [www.randolphusa.com] (the “ **Website** “) or when you place an order, fill out a form, or provide Randolph with your name, mailing address, billing address, email address, telephone number, credit card information, or any other personal information, and explains how we collect, use, maintain, protect, and, in some circumstances, disclose that information.

Certain information Randolph collects will only be done with your consent, other information may be required in order to complete Randolph’s contractual obligations or is necessary for Randolph to operate the Website.

This policy applies to information Randolph collects:

  * On the Website
  * When you email or otherwise exchange electronic messages with Randolph
  * When you place an order
  * When you fill out a form
  * When you enter your email address, mailing address, billing address, phone number, credit card information, or any other personal information
  * When you call Randolph
  * When registering or commenting on the Website.

It does not apply to information collected by:

  * Any third party including:
    * Randolph’s distributors or retail establishments carrying its products
    * Any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from the Website.

Please read this policy carefully to understand Randolph’s policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with Randolph’s policies and practices, your choice is not to provide us with the requested information or to decline to use the Website. By accessing or using the Website, and/or by providing Randolph with your information, you agree to this privacy policy. This policy may change from time to time (see Changes to Our Privacy Policy). Your continued use of the Website after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates.

 **What Personal Information Does Randolph Engineering Eyewear Collect?**

Randolph collects and stores information about you both by asking you to provide this information to us, and, in some circumstances, by gathering the information automatically.

 **Information You Give Us:** Randolph receives and stores any information you enter on the Website or give us in any other way. _[Click here to see examples of what we collect.]_ You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of Randolph’s services or features. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as fulfilling your orders, responding to your requests, customizing future shopping for you, improving Randolph’s stores, and communicating with you.

 **Automatic Information We Collect:** Randolph receives and stores certain types of information whenever you interact with Randolph. For example, like many websites, we use “cookies,” and obtain certain types of information when your web browser accesses the Website. _[Click here to see examples of the information we receive.]_

 **Email Communications:** To help us make emails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open email from us, if your computer supports such capabilities. If you do not want to receive email or other mail from us, please press the unsubscribe button on any of our emails or contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

 **Information from Other Sources:** Randolph might receive information about you from other sources and add it to its account information. [ _Click here to see examples of the information we receive.]_

 **How Do We Use Cookies?**

Randolph uses different types of cookies to automatically collect certain data to improve your experience of the Website, and to allow us to track certain information about how visitors use the Website. These include:

  *  **Cookies (or browser cookies).** A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. When you first visit the Website, you are asked whether you want to accept cookies. You may decline or accept them at that time, though declining to accept cookies may prevent you from using the Website’s features.  You may also refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of the Website. Unless you have declined cookies when you first visit or adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, Randolph’s system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to the Website.
  *  **Flash Cookies.** Certain features of the Website may use locally stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from, and on the Website. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings that are used for browser cookies. For information about managing your privacy and security settings for Flash cookies, see What Choices Do I Have.
  *  **Web Beacons.** Pages of the Website and Randolph’s emails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that permit Randolph, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an email, and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity).
  *  **Social Media Pixel Tags.** Randolph uses pixel tags, a type of web beacon, on social media sites, to serve relevant and targeted advertisements to you during or after your visits to our social media presence.
  *  **Affiliate Sales Trackers.** In certain instances, Randolph tracks the sites from which its visitors clicked onto the Website to allow Randolph to pay a referral commission on any purchases that a visitor completes during the visit.

 **Might I Encounter Any Third Party Cookies?**

Some content or applications on the Website are served by third parties, including advertisers, ad networks and servers, content providers, and application providers. These third parties may use cookies alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use the Website. The information they collect may be associated with your personal information or they may collect information, including personal information, about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based (behavioral) advertising or other targeted content.

Randolph does not control these third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you have any questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should contact the responsible provider directly.

 **  
How Do We Use Your Information?**

Randolph uses information that it collects about you or that you provide to it, including any personal information, in order to:

  * Present the Website and its contents to you
  * Process and ship any orders to you
  * Provide you with notices about your accounts or orders
  * Carry out Randolph’s obligations and enforce its rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and Randolph, including for billing and collection
  * Notify you about changes to the Website or any products or services Randolph offers or provides though it
  * Allow you to participate in interactive features on the Website
  * Provide you with information about your recent visits and to store information about products placed in your shopping cart
  * Determine your general location to enable you to locate nearby stores or access information relevant to you based on your location
  * In any other way Randolph may describe when you provide the information
  * For any other purpose, with your consent.

Randolph may also, with your consent, use your information to contact you about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you want to remove yourself from this list at any time, please press the unsubscribe button on any of our emails or contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)  For more information, see What Choices do I Have?

 **  
Do You Share the Personal Information with Others?**

Randolph values the information it has about its customers, and is not in the business of selling it to others. We do occasionally need to share your information for the purpose of delivering the purchased product or service, to otherwise conduct business with you or to comply with legal obligations.  For example, under certain circumstances, Randolph may need to disclose collected personal information in order to:

  * Fulfill the purpose for which you provide it, such as to arrange shipping of products to you
  * Disclose to trusted third parties, who are bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential, to support Randolph’s business, and to use it only for the purposes for which Randolph discloses it to them
  * Comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request
  * Carry out Randolph’s obligations and enforce its rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and Randolph, including for billing and collection
  * Protect the rights, property, or safety of Randolph Engineering Eyewear, its employees, customers, or others, including exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction
  * Provide the collected personal information to a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of Randolph Engineering Eyewear’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by Randolph Engineering Eyewear about the Website users is among the assets transferred
  * Fulfill any other purpose disclosed by Randolph when you provide the information
  * Comply with your instructions or, if allowed to do so, with your consent.

Randolph may disclose aggregated information about its users and information that does not identify any individual without restriction.

 **  
How Do You Protect My Information?**

Randolph implements a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information. We work with Authorize.net, a payment processor, to ensure secure and efficient processing of your customer data. Authorize.net uses a secure, encrypted server, and ensures that all supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted on Authorize.net’s servers.  We do not receive or have access to your credit card number – that information is maintained only by Authorize.net.  The information on Authorize.net, is only accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, who are required to keep the information confidential. For more information on Authorize.net’s security and privacy policy, please click here:  https://www.authorize.net/about-us/privacy/

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where Randolph has given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of the Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the Website, like message boards. The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of the Website.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although Randolph does its best to protect your personal information, it cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to the Website. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk.

 **Can I Post My Opinions on the Website?**

Some parts of the Website allow you to post comments, reviews or questions (“User Contributions”) to be published or displayed on public areas of the Website. Your User Contributions are posted on and transmitted to others at your own risk.  Please be aware that Randolph cannot control the actions of other users of the Website with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions. Therefore, Randolph cannot and does not guarantee that your User Contributions will not be viewed by unauthorized persons.  If you would like to make comments, reviews, or ask questions in a manner that is not visible to other users, please feel free to contact Randolph at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

 **What Choices Do I Have?**

You can always choose not to provide information, even though it might be needed to make a purchase or to take advantage of some features of the Website.

You can decline to accept cookies, set your browser to block cookies, or erase Randolph’s cookies from your computer, though doing so may prevent some aspects of the Website from working properly.

If you no longer want to receive email or other mail from Randolph, please press the unsubscribe button on any of our emails or contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

If you want to exercise your rights over your data pursuant to GDPR, please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

 **  
How Long Do You Keep My Data?**

Randolph only keeps your personal data for as long as necessary, and for the purposes for which Randolph collected it.

 **Can I Access or Correct My Information?**

You can review and change your personal information by logging into the Website and visiting your account profile page.

You may also send Randolph an email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to request access to, correct, or delete any personal information that you have provided to Randolph. We may not be able to delete your personal information without also deleting your user account. We also may not accommodate a request to change or delete information if it is believed that the change would violate any law or legal requirement, or cause the information to be incorrect.

If you wish to delete your User Contributions from the Website please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), but please be aware that copies of your User Contributions may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or might have been copied or stored by other Website users.

 **Children Under the Age of 13**

The Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on the Website. Randolph does not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on the Website or on/through any of its features, register on the Website, make any purchases through the Website, use any of the interactive or public comment features of the Website, or provide any information about yourself to Randolph, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn that we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, the information will be deleted. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

 **  
Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of the Website that are California residents to request certain information regarding Randolph’s disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

 **  
GDPR**

The European Union has implemented the General Data Protection Regulation, commonly called “GDPR.”  Randolph’s customers who are European Data Subject, as defined in the regulation, may have additional rights.  If you have questions about your rights under GDPR, please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

 **  
Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

It is Randolph’s policy to post any changes it makes to its privacy policy on this page with a notice that the privacy policy has been updated on the Website home page. If Randolph makes material changes to how it treats its users’ personal information, we will notify you by email to the primary email address specified in your account and/or through a notice on the Website home page. The date the privacy policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. You are responsible for ensuring that we have an up-to-date, active, and deliverable email address for you, and for periodically visiting the Website and this privacy policy to check for any changes.

 **  
How Can I Contact You?**

To ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and Randolph’s privacy practices, contact us at:

1.800.541.1405  
(Toll Free US & CAN only)

Randolph Engineering, Inc.  
26 Thomas Patten Drive  
Randolph, MA 02368

Call Us Internationally  
781.961.6070

Send Us a Fax  
781.394.2408

EMAIL US  
[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

 **Information You Give Us:**

Examples of the information you give Randolph includes:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on the Website, including your name, email address, mailing and billing addresses, telephone numbers, user names and passwords, zip codes, and credit card information
  * Information you provide when you post comments, reviews, or ask questions on the Website
  * Information you provide when you enter a contest or promotion sponsored by Randolph
  * Records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses), if you contact Randolph
  * Your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes
  * Details of transactions you carry out through the Website and of the fulfillment of your orders
  * Your search queries on the Website.
  * [DESCRIBE ANY OTHER TYPES OF INFORMATION THE USER PROVIDES]

 **Information from Other Sources** :

Randolph occasionally works with partners to interact with its clients by, for example, managing its customer surveys, organizing contests, or other promotions.  Randolph also interacts with its customers over social media platforms, and sometimes combines information that its customers post on social media platforms with information it has from the Website.  Additionally, in certain instances, Randolph tracks the sites from which its visitors clicked onto the Website to allow Randolph to pay a referral commission on any purchases that visitor completes during the visit.

 **  
Automatic Information:**

As you navigate through and interact with the Website, Randolph may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions, and patterns, including:

  * The Internet Protocol addresses associated with you
  * The User Agents associated with your Browser
  * The parts of the Website that you visit and what you do while you are there.

The information Randolph automatically collects does not include your name or other directly personal data, but we may maintain it or associate it with personal information we collect in other ways.

 **  
Why Do We Collect this Information?**

The automatically collected information helps Randolph improve the Website and to deliver a better and more personalized service, by enabling Randolph to:

  * Improve your shopping experience (saving cart history/session data)
  * Store information about your preferences, allowing Randolph to customize the Website according to your individual interests
  * Speed up your searches
  * Recognize you when you return to the Website
  * Help you find your nearest dealer
  * Allow you to manage your orders/account
  * Estimate Randolph’s audience size and usage patterns.
